James Bechet

JAMESBECHET.COM

EMPLOYMENT

Pumpup

Front-End Engineer, Toronto 2 years (2014 - 2016)

Worked closely with designers and developers to drive user retention. Developed front-end and back-end features to be enjoyed by million of users.

Geckoboard

Full-Stack Engineer Intern, London 6 months (Summer 2014)

Implemented and optimized several integrations, which enables businesses to visualize their relevant data in real-time.

Jolicloud

Front-End Engineer Intern, Paris 6 months (Summer 2013)

Deployed several features to improve the user experience. Examined data to make product decisions.

Capital Fund Managment

Data Engineer Intern, Paris 5 months (Summer 2012)

Prototyped and developed a cloud-like cluster storage. Using hashing algorithms to improve the current storage system.

Survision

Software Engineer Intern, Paris 7 months - Part time (2011 - 2012)

Prototyped and developed a module to communicate with a high definition camera manufactured by Sony and using an open source SDK.

OTHER PROJECTS

Gymaholic

Full-Stack Engineer 2016

Developed the whole front-end and back-end using the newest web technologies like React and Redux. The website is mobile-friendly and has thousands of visitors daily.

Tumblr Post Tags

Front-End Engineer 2013

Created the chrome extension to help users to manage and post their favorite tags on the microblogging platform Tumblr. The extension is used by hundreds of users.

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Engineer with a focus on simple and innovative products.
Experienced with frontend and back-end development.

SKILLS

Development: Javascript, React, Redux, Flux, Node.js, Redis, Sequelize, SASS, CSS, HTML, C++, Python

Tools: Git, Atom, Sublime Text, Photoshop, Illustrator

EDUCATION

SUPINFO

2 years (2012 - 2014) Master Of Science San Francisco, Paris

EPITECH

3 years (2009 - 2012) Bachelor Of Science Paris

CONTACT

jamesbechet@gmail.com jamesbechet.com